Hey.
You're late, dumbass.
Sorry.
You shouldn't be telling me that.
Let's go.
The black mirror in the sky is called the God Gate!
It's the gateway to the passage that'll guide the God of Creation back to this world!
His avatar and the Trinity are within!
On their way back!
I, the Flame-Haired Blazing-Eyed Hunter, and my companions here will now head in to prevent their return!
Charge!
Light my fire
Light My Fire
Light my fire.
Light
Ima tokihanate himeta omoi wo
今解き放て  秘めた思いを
Release the Feelings you've kept hidden
Mu ni kaeru genjitsu tachikiru tame ni
無に帰る現実　断ち切るために
to rid yourself of the reality that returns to nothing.
Unmei ga hitsuzen da to shitatte
運命が必然だとしたって
Even if fate is bound to be,
Nobody can predict what will happen
Nobody can predict what will happen.
dict
what
will
hap
pen
Hisshi ni aragattekun da
必死に抗ってくんだ
That's why we fight.
Sono hitomi ni utsushita mirai wo
その瞳に映した未来を
To seize the future seen in our eyes.
Kono te ni
この手に
With our Hands!
Shout out onore no sonzai
Shout out 己の存在
Shout out your existence
Shout
Sakebe whoa
叫べ  whoa
Scream it!
whoa
Shout out
Shout out!
Sh
o
ut
out
Shout out donna konnan ga
Shout out どんな困難が
Shout out! No matter what challenges
Kono saki ni matteyou to mo
この先に  待ってようとも
may be waiting ahead.
Wow! Whoa!
Wow!
Whoa!
Light my fire
Light My Fire
Light my fire.
Light
Welcome back, Satou-kun.
Yoshida-san.
You should've waited inside.
I asked her to stay outside.
I knew we were going to run here, so I wanted her tell us who was first.
I won like I said I would, right?
Yup.
What the hell is that?
You're not coming in?
It's all right. I saw that you came back.
Like she said.
I got you home in one piece, so my job's done, too.
H-Hey-
Did you come back for us?
No, right?
But...
You know how...
...Sleeping Beauty woke up, right?
See ya.
Please let me know when she wakes up.
O-Okay.
Affections Reach
What are you doing?
Marcosius.
What are you doing here?
Because I heard you were coming home, duh.
But why?
I'm not a Peeping Tom.
B-But...
Isn't that why you came back?
Well...
Yes.
You heard the whole story from Eita and the girl, right?
I suppose.
Then get a move on.
Stop making me lecture.
But I...
Go.
Yes.
Keisaku.
When an opportunity to be cool presents itself, nothing is over the top.
Be a man.
Thanks...
...Marcosius.
Save it until everything's good and done.
I just got back, Margery-san.
Margery-san.
I heard about everything that's happened to you.
What the Silver you've been chasing actually is.
How the hundreds of years you've spent chasing him turned out to be meaningless.
But for us, it did have meaning.
Tanaka, Shana-chan, Yoshida-san and Oga-chan.
Even for Sakai, too.
Above all, it meant everything to me.
No matter what anyone else thinks of you, or even what you think of yourself,
to me, your existence defines my world.
Since I chose to live so that you'll keep living, you're my reason to go on living.
And when I heard that you needed me, it made me happy.
Feeling this joy...
...I came to realize that I am living my life for you.
When you wake up, I'd like you to know my feelings.
Marge-
I heard your voice.
And Eita and Kazumi's voices, too, when I was on the brink of totally breaking down.
He hasn't done anything for you yet!
There are people who already love you!
In that moment, I did think of you and felt the feelings within me.
I was surprised by that,
then I doubted myself
and finally, I was confused.
That's why I went to sleep.
Why?
I thought, if what I felt were really true,
then I could delay my breakdown until after I confirmed them.
And did you?
Enough to keep me from breaking down.
That's enough.
More than enough.
Enough for me.
Thank you.
Did I insult you at all?
I don't care.
As long as you're here.
That's not good enough.
So as a woman, I'll ask you as a man.
Keisaku.
By risking your mission and your life for me...
Do you love me?
Yes! I love you!
Do you remember how I once said Flame Haze are so strong, they can't even love others with everything they have?
Y-Yes.
I can make others equally strong, if only for a short time.
If I hadn't walled myself off from you, you'd have come too close to me.
Right?
Until now, it had to be that way.
But now...
See for yourself.
What's that?
A bird, yet not a bird.
Hmm.
It must be one of the Flame Haze that banished the God of Creation here centuries ago.
Is it telling us to follow?
Seems that way.
The situation favours our thanks for the surprise attack.
According to reports from the front, the fortress' defence units are out.
So their base was rather short-handed, since they weren't expecting a surprise attack like this.
François, show us all activity in the surrounding area.
Yes, right away.
In range of my radar, there's a group coming from the north.
I assume it's a unit that was acting as a defence line for Bal Masqué coming back.
Another enemy unit, nearer than the previous one, is coming from the south.
The defence units are small in size, so they will not be difficult to deal with, but...
The biggest concerns are their primary forces that withdrew from the east and west.
I believe neither will arrive until tomorrow.
Some of our men are working on intercepting and chasing withdrawing enemies, but...
The advantage we hold now is limited to a very short window.
The end of the window being when either main force arrives from the east or west.
How much can we accomplish in the given time?
First, we'll send half of the reserves to reinforce the forces fighting near the God Gate.
They need only act as a diversion.
Our objective is to split the enemy force in two.
Samuel, I'd like you to take the remaining reserves and lead a charge into Seireiden.
Yes, Ma'am.
Currently, both the avatar of the God of Destruction and the Trinity are absent.
Let's take full advantage of this.
We're short on men.
But we cannot let them take Seireiden, which is filled with secrets, for even a moment.
I must buy time until the arrival of more forces.
When the unit to the west and the Amplifier, Haborym, arrive, there will be no further problems.
But in this situation, we cannot maintain our defences until their arrival.
I have no choice.
What's this?!
The source of the tremors is moving!
Could it be?!
Decarabia!
Coming out to the frontlines now?
How very unlike him.
What?
It seems attacking Decarabia isn't causing any damage!
And it looks like all the attacks that were effective against the Tomogara aren't anymore.
He's using an unrestricted teleport spell on himself to evade attacks.
And is casting unrestricted protect spells on the others.
It's a simple spell that's not meant for wide-area use, so he's casting it on each and every one of them in the field.
What a ridiculous act.
He must have shown himself to simultaneously maintain multiple spells out here.
But this act is...
He's not going for endurance here.
Not suicide, but a desperate act.
Are his remaining forces so depleted that he has to risk his life?
Or are his reinforcements close enough that they'll be here if he can prolong the battle just enough?
It seems I cannot sit back any longer.
We'll go straight at it.
Construct a bridge, a road in the sky.
Is that okay with you, Zirnitra?
Confirmed.
Commence mission, Demantius!
Disarray.
Attack force.
Fall in.
Your name is Honour.
Awaken, calm hill!
Everyone, form ranks!
Attention!
Charge!
The blizzard stopped.
With better visibility, it is easier to aim.
I can only perform one shot.
So I'll put everything into the one shot.
I see you!
That was very well done, but didn't you use too much power?
But it was worth it.
Now Samuel can-
C-Chief Commander Sawallisch!
To the west! A large army suddenly appeared!
Our radar was active!
That flame is...
Amplifier, Haborym.
The western force made it all the way back in this short of a time?
The flock of birds was to conceal them all?
They tricked us well.
The enemy's reinforcements are here!
Crap! They have us surrounded!
So our time has already run out.
Margery-san?!
What?
What's with that look?
I-I'm sorry.
This thing you brought back.
I read it through.
The plan Sophie came up with.
The Calm. Crossroads. Then Ebbing Tide.
You should hurry up and get ready, too!
We need to get going.
You're coming with me, aren't you?
I see an unrestricted spell around hidden Rinne in the castle up ahead.
It's triple-layered.
Concealment, communication interdictor and the third is unknown.
That makes a total of twelve obstacles ~de arimasuna.
Like others, their objectives are...
...to delay and protect.
Ah, but it's dangerous that the last one is an unknown spell.
First, we must approach cautiously.
But hey, that Judgement eye is really handy.
Can you trade with mine? It can't do anything besides destroy stuff.
Ow.
It's surprising that you want the power to see over the power to destroy.
Shut up.
anata wo terashita kousai ga
あなたを照らした光彩が
If the brilliance that illuminated you
watashi no naka ni mo aru nara
わたしの記憶にも在るなら
also exists inside of my memories,
I’m sure that we can go
sure
that
we
can
subete wo shoumei shite ikou
全てを証明していこう
let's go prove all the reasons
sonzai shite iku tame no riyuu wo
存在していく為の理由を
there are to exist.
Inside of Kaos I say
In
side
Where can I get the real love and fate,
Where
can
I
get
the
real
love
and
fate,
right now?
right
now?
How can I make you know
How
can
I
make
you
know
my heart is with you, hey?
my
heart
is
with
you,
hey?
hito wa dare mo wasurete iku
人は誰も忘れていく
Everyone eventually forgets everything,
itameta kizuato mo
痛めた傷跡も
even their pains.
toki no nagare miokuru tabi ni
時間の流れ見送る度に
As time goes by,
usureru kanjou
薄れる感情
other emotions fade as well.
dakedo kore ijou misugoshi takunakute
だけどこれ以上見過ごしたくなくて
But I can't just ignore this anymore.
Back&forth
Back
な
く
&
て
forth
kokorojuu sakende yamanai
心中叫んでやまない
I won't stop shouting from my heart!
叫ん
Time over kiete iku zanzou sore wa anata sonomono dakara
Time over 消えていく残像それは あなたそのものだから
(Time over) That I'll never leave you, who I love, alone again.
Time
So now that you and I
So
now
that
you
and
I can’t live life without you by my side...
I
can’t
live
life
with
out
you
by
my
side...
「I’ll believe...」 kodoku mo innen sae
「I’ll believe..」孤独も因縁さえ
"I'll believe..." Even in my lonely fate.
「I’ll
be
lieve...」
lieve..」
Yeah, yeah
Yeah,
shakunetsu no kiroku no kakera
灼熱の記録の欠片
There will be a brightness that shines tomorrow
sha
灼
yeah
Asu wo utsusu brightness
現在を映すbrightness
from my burning memories.
bright
Can see your light
Can
see
your
ness
light
Because the brilliance that illuminated you
anata wo terashita kousai ga
あなたを照らした光彩が
watashi no naka ni mo aru nara
わたしの記憶にも在るなら
also exists inside of my memories.
I’m sure that we can go
sure
that
we
can
subete wo shoumei shite ikou
全てを証明していこう
su
全
So let's confirm everything, since,
kyouzon shite iku ashita wo 「I’ll believe..」
共存していく未来を「I'll believe..」
in the future where we'll coexist, "I'll believe..."
「I’ll
「I'll
be
lieve..」
Leaving the battle against Sabrac to Wilhelmina and the others, Shana goes after Yuuji.
But Hecate's ceremony has begun, and the true Serpent of the Ritual's roar echoes across the land.
Next time on Shakugan no Shana Final:
Oath
Oath.